Guide to the University of Pittsburgh Archives Moving Images Collection, ca. 1928-2001 UA.Film.Video
ULS Archives & Special Collections
University of Pittsburgh Archives Moving Images Collection
ca. 1928-2010
ULS Archives & Special Collections
University of Pittsburgh. Archives Service Center
UA.Film.Video
2358 items
This is a collection of over 2,300 films and videos that mainly pertain to University of Pittsburgh athletics as well as University events and history. The collection (ca. 1928-ca. 2001) ranges from interviews and speeches by prominent University figures to sports highlight videos and University institutional messages. Types of media in this collection include VHS tapes, Betacam SP tapes, ¾ Inch U-matic tapes, and 16 millimeter film.
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of a very small percentage of the collection are available on DVDs located in the Archives Service Center.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Various playback devices are needed to watch the film and/or videos, which are available onsite at the Archives Service Center. Please make an appointment with the Media Curator before viewing. Although not displayed in the finding aid, data entered into Archivists' Toolkit can inform ASC staff about the material itself, such as length, type, condition, etc.
Previous Citation
University of Pittsburgh Archives Moving Images, ca. 1928-2001, UA.Film.Video, University Archives, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into five series, then within sections that comprise Film and/or Video. The Sports series contains subseries alphabetized by sport name, then film and/or video sections.
Series I. Sports
Series II. Historical
Series III. Promotional
Series IV. Lectures
Series V. Assorted
Please note that the film/video within each section are not arranged in any particular order (e.g., chronological), but rather as they were found in each respective box.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Scope and Content Notes
This is a collection of over 2,300 films and videos that mainly pertain to University of Pittsburgh athletics as well as University events and history. The collection (ca. 1928-ca. 2001) ranges from interviews and speeches by prominent University figures, such as Dr. Wesley Posvar and Tony Dorsett, to sports highlight videos and University institutional messages. It notably contains much footage of classic Pitt football games, including prominent bowl games. It also contains numerous videos and films which pertain to the city of Pittsburgh as well as miscellaneous topics that do not directly relate to the University of Pittsburgh. Types of media in this collection include VHS tapes, Betacam SP tapes, ¾ Inch U-matic tapes, and 16 millimeter film.
Swimming -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Wrestling -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Volleyball -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Tennis -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Gymnastics -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Soccer films; Soccer -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Football films; Basketball films; Football -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Basketball -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Track and field -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Filmed lectures; Filmed speeches; Filmed sports events; Sports films; University of Pittsburgh; Speeches, addresses, etc. -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Lectures and lecturing -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Athletics -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Video recordings (physical artifacts); Motion pictures; Sports; Videocassettes; Promotional films; Commencement ceremonies -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Greek letter societies -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; University of Pittsburgh -- History; University of Pittsburgh -- Track and field; University of Pittsburgh -- Tennis; University of Pittsburgh -- Wrestling; University of Pittsburgh -- Students -- Societies, etc.; University of Pittsburgh -- Soccer; University of Pittsburgh -- Gymnastics; University of Pittsburgh -- Football; University of Pittsburgh -- Basketball; University of Pittsburgh -- Volleyball; Khrushchev, Nikita Sergeevich; Fonda, Jane; Allen, Robert T.; Posvar, Wesley Wentz; Miller, William M.
- Sports, I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains over 2,000 sports-related films and videos, including footage of games, practices, and interviews with prominent sports figures. Through this collection, one can view sports events (mainly football and basketball) from throughout the twentieth century, including a few football games from the 1930s.
  - Baseball, 1.
    This subseries contains 20 videos, mostly from the 1990s, from the Pitt baseball program. This includes game and season highlights, notably including three tapes of footage from the 1995 NCAA baseball championship.
    - Video, 25 items
      - Baseball - Pitt at PC (game 2) - Reel 2 Dub, April 5, 1992; Betacam SP 90 Minute (Box 44, Video 1011)
      - Baseball - Pitt at Providence #2 (Dub), April 5, 1992; Betacam SP 30 Minute Tape 3 of ? (Box 48, Video 1105)
      - Baseball, March 23, 1994; Betacam SP 30 Minute Needs Case (Box 6, Video 108)
      - Baseball, May 16, 1994; Betacam SP 30 Minute (Box 40, Video 861)
      - 1995 NCAA Baseball Regional, Betacam SP 30 Minute Tape 1 of ? Needs Case (Box 26, Video 502)
      - 1995 NCAA Baseball Regional, Betacam SP 30 Minute Needs Case (Box 26, Video 502)
      - Pitt Baseball 1995, Betacam SP 30 Minute (Box 6, Video 99)
      - Pitt Baseball 1995, April 2, 1995; Betacam SP 30 Minute Needs Case (Box 6, Video 107)
      - Pitt Baseball, April 5, 1992; VHS T-30 (Box 6, Video 105)
      - Pitt Baseball vs. Akron, April 18, 1996; Betacam SP 30 Minute Three Rivers Stadium (Box 32, Video 640)
      - NCAA Baseball - OKLA ST vs PITT / CAL WINNE … Interviews, May 27, 1995; Betacam SP 30 Minute Tape 1 of ? Needs Case (Box 29, Video 561)
      - Baseball - Master Tape, March 31, 1999; Betacam SP 30 Minute Needs Case (Box 44, Video 1001)
      - Baseball #1, April 21, 1999; Betacam SP 30 Minute Tape 1 of ? Needs Case (Box 44, Video 989)
      - Pitt Baseball Hilites, March 30, 1996; Betacam SP 30 Minute (Box 32, Video 641)
      - Baseball Highlight - Home Plate 1, April 18, ????; Betacam SP 30 Minute Tape 1 of ? Needs Case (Box 44, Video 982)
      - Baseball Highlight - Home Plate 2, April 18, ????; Betacam SP 30 Minute Tape 2 of ? Needs Case (Box 44, Video 1000)
      - Baseball Highlight - Home Plate 3, April 18, ????; Betacam SP 30 Minute Tape 3 of ? Needs Case (Box 44, Video 984)
      - Baseball Hilight - Roving 2, April 18, ????; Betacam SP 30 Minute Tape 2 of ? Needs Case (Box 44, Video 999)
      - Baseball Highlight - Roving 3, April 18, ????; Betacam SP 30 Minute Tape 3 of ? Needs Case (Box 44, Video 983)
      - Pitt vs Uconn Baseball, unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute (Box 6, Video 116)
  - Basketball, 2.
    This subseries of basketball-related videos includes subdivisions that denote whether the basketball videos pertain to either Men's or Women's basketball. There are 260 items altogether.
    - Film, 8 items
      This section contains eight Men's basketball films from the early-to-middle part of the twentieth century. This notably includes one reel of footage from the 1941 NCAA Men's basketball championship.
      - 1941 #7 North Carolina vs. Pitt (playoffs), 16mm film Media Room 6/6/4 (Box 6, Reel 856)
      - 1948-1949 #1 Bradley vs. Pitt, 16mm film Reel 1 Media Room 6/6/4 (Box 6, Reel 857)
      - 1948-1949 #1 Bradley vs. Pitt, 16mm film Reel 2 Media Room 6/6/4 (Box 6, Reel 858)
      - 1948-1949 #1 Bradley vs. Pitt, 16mm film Reel 3 Media Room 6/6/4 (Box 6, Reel 859)
      - 1955 #6 Westminster vs. Pitt, 16mm film Media Room 6/6/4 (Box 6, Reel 855)
      - 1972-1973 Duquesne vs. Pitt, 16mm film Reel 1 Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 6, Reel 980)
      - 1972-1973 #2 Duquesne vs. Pitt, 16mm film Reel 2 Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 6, Reel 979)
      - 1973 Army vs. Pitt, 16mm film Reel 2 Media Room 6/6/5 (Box 6, Reel 981)
      - Basketball Fundamentals wiht Henry Clifford "Doc" Carlson, 1950-1953
    - Video
      - Men's, 194 items
        This section contains much footage of the Pitt Men's team, mostly from the 1980s and 1990s. Numerous videos in this series can give viewers a chance to see the likes of Sean Miller, Charles Smith, and Ralph Willard. Altogether there are 194 videos.
        - Pitt Basketball 1941, unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute (Box 25, Video 496)
        - BB Games Master 1973-74 Kirk Bruce, 1973-1974; VHS T-120 Kirk Bruce (Box 4, Video 74)
        - Pitt Basketball (Reel #1) - Start to end halftime, December 14, 1985; 1 Inch Videotape 480 Master Broadcast Tape 1 of ? (Box 50, Video 1128)
        - Pitt vs. St. John's - Reel #3, December 24, 1985; 1 Inch Videotape Tape 3 of ? (Box 51, Video 1137)
        - Pitt / Boston Basketball, February 22, 1986; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 Tape 1 of ? (Box 10, Video 387)
        - Pitt / Boston Basketball, February 22, 1986; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 Tape 2 of ? (Box 10, Video 386)
        - Pitt / Boston, Feburary 22, 1986; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 30 Tape 3 of ? (Box 10, Video 390)
        - Pitt / St. John Basketball (Reel 1), January 4, 1986; 1 Inch Videotape 480 Master Broadcast (Box 52, Video 1153)
        - Pitt/Georgetown Basketball #1, March 1, 1986; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 Tape 1 of ? (Box 4, Video 391)
        - NCAA Hoops Georgetown/Pittsburgh, January 2, 1986; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCA-60K (Box 1, Video 457)
        - Pitt/Georgetown Basketball (#2), March 1, 1986; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 Tape 2 of ? (Box 1, Video 454)
        - Pitt/Georgetown #3, March 1, 1986; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 30 (Box 27, Video 528)
        - Pitt Basketball Tape #1, December 6, 1986; 1 Inch Videotape 480 Master Broadcast Tape 1 of ? (Box 51, Video 1136)
        - Pitt Basketball - Tape #2, December 6, 1986; 1 Inch Videotape 480 Master Broadcast Tape 2 of ? (Box 51, Video 1135)
        - Pitt vs. Kansas Rainbow Classic, December 28, 1986; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 Tape 2 of 3 (Box 4, Video 1379)
        - Pitt vs. Kansas - Rainbow Classic - Tape 3 of 3 (if necessary), December 28, 1986; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 30 Tape 3 of 3 (Box 27, Video 523)
        - Pitt vs Wisconsin, December 31, 1986; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 Tape 1 of 3 (Box 4, Video 252)
        - Pitt - WVU Basketball 1, December 13, 1986; 1 Inch Videotape 480 Master Broadcast Tape 1 of ? (Box 51, Video 1138)
        - Pitt - WVU Basketball 2, December 13, 1986; 1 Inch Videotape 480 Master Broadcast Tape 2 of ? (Box 51, Video 1139)
        - Pitt vs. St. Johns - 1987, 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 Tape 2 of 3 (Box 24, Video 723)
        - Pitt vs. Boston College, January 24, 1987; 3/4 Inch U-Matic UCA 60 Tape 1 of 2 (Box 4, Video 793)
        - Pitt vs. Boston College, January 30, 1988; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 Tape 1 of 2 (Box 4, Video 1368)
        - Pitt vs. Seton Hall (1), March 6, 1987; 3/4 Inch U-matic Tape 2 of 2 (Box 1, Video 455)
        - Pitt vs WVU Basketball (Men's), December 12, 1987; 1 Inch Videotape 480 Master Broadcast Tape 1 of 2 (Box 52, Video 1151)
        - Pitt Basketball Special, November 20, 1987; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA30 (Box 1, Video 456)
        - Pitt vs. WVU Basketball, December 12, 1987; 1 Inch Videotape 480 Master Broadcast Tape 2 of 2 (Box 52, Video 1149)
        - Pitt vs. Georgetown, January 6, 1988; 1 Inch Videotape 480 Master Broadcast Tape 2 of 2 (Box 52, Video 1148)
        - Pitt vs Georgetown, January 6, 1988; 1 Inch Videotape 480 Master Broadcast Tape 1 of 2 (Box 52, Video 1145)
        - Pitt vs Villanova, January 16, 1988; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 Tape 1 of 2 (Box 15, Video 1387)
        - Pitt vs. Villanova, January 16, 1988; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 Tape 2 of 2 (Box 10, Video 1388)
        - Pitt Basketball Special, February 29, 1988; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 30 (Box 4, Video 1396)
        - Pitt Basketball One of Two, March 12, 1988; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA60 (Box 1, Video 453)
        - Basketball Highlights - 1988-1989, unknown; VHS T-30 (Box 42, Video 913)
        - Pitt Hoops 88-89 - "Team in Transition" Show #3 (Master), March 4, 1989; 1 Inch Videotape 480 Master Broadcast (Box 51, Video 1133)
        - Pitt Basketball '88-'89 - "Team in Transition" Show #1 (Master), November 18, 1988; 1 Inch Videotape 480 Master Broadcast (Box 51, Video 1134)
        - McTewon - Villanova at Pitt 1988-1989, VHS T120 (Box 4, Video 226)
        - Darelle Porter Feature for 1989 - Tournament of Champions, 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 20 (Box 7, Video 118)
        - Basketball Villanova at Pitt 1989 W 85-73, VHS T60 (Box 4, Video 227)
        - Seton Hall vs. Pittsburgh, January 20, 1990; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA60 Tape 2 of 2 Recorded from Satellite (Box 1, Video 451)
        - "Sean Miller on the Tonight Show", ca. 1991; 3/4 Inch U-matic MBR 20s Dee Thompson (Box 39, Video 781)
        - Sean Miller 1991 PSA, VHS T-120 (Box 39, Video 805)
        - 1991-1992 Big East Basketball Highlight Video, unknown; VHS T-120 (Box 32, Video 655)
        - D'arcy / Bill Flemming Prod. 1991 College Basketball Preview East, November 21, 1990; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 30 25:08 (Box 10, Video 180)
        - Pitt Basketball Pre-Game Show, February 16, 1991; 3/4 Inch U-matic (Box 10, Video 178)
        - Pitt Basketball Pre-Game Show, March 2, 1991; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 30 (Box 10, Video 181)
        - 1992-93 Pitt Bball Arena Ticket Spot, unknown; VHS T-5 Needs Case (Box 40, Video 857)
        - SportsBeat College Basketball Preview - Coaches - Evens, Carrol, and Durham, November 19, 1993; VHS T-60 Needs Case (Box 17, Video 308)
        - Pitt vs. Georgetown, February 16, 1994; VHS T120 (Box 3, Video 210)
        - Best of "Saturday Hoops Reel", 1994-1995; Betacam SP 10 Minute Produced by: Terri Schindler and Chris Furrow Edit by: Ed Dimeglio (Box 4, Video 340)
        - Rebound Pass Special Plays 1997, VHS (Box 10, Video 61)
        - Panthers Basketball with Coach Ralph Willard Show #6, February 8, 1997; VHS T-120 Needs Case (Box 17, Video 281)
        - 1997 Panther Basketball With Ralph Willard, unknown; VHS Needs Case (Box 15, Video 244)
        - Beta Test B-Ball #1, 1998-1999; Betacam SP 30 Minute (Box 4, Video 70)
        - Panther Basketball with Ralph Willard Show #2, January 17, 1998; VHS T-120 Needs Case (Box 17, Video 289)
        - Test Tape Men's Basketball 1998-1999 #2, Betacam SP 30 Minute (Box 4, Video 76)
        - Panther Basketball with Ralph Willard Show #1, January 3, 1998; VHS (Box 9, Video 160)
        - "The Place To Be" Basketball Edit - 30 Sec., January 22, 1999; Betacam SP (Box 4, Video 75)
        - University of Pittsburgh Men's Press Conference, March 8, 1999; Betacam SP 30 Minute (Box 17, Video 305)
        - Headshots Men's B-Ball, October 14, 1999; Betacam SP 30 Minute (Box 4, Video 73)
        - Bankshot Basketball, unknown; VHS 607-724-9217 (Box 4, Video 338)
        - Jump Ball TRT :35, unknown; Betacam SP :35 (Box 9, Video 300)
        - Pitt Prime Time - January 27, VHS T-120HS Needs Case (Box 9, Video 164)
        - Syracuse @ Pittsburgh, January 19, 2000; Betacam SP 30 Minute Michael Molinari (Box 17, Video 292)
        - Seton Hall @ Pittsburgh, January 16, 2000; Betacam SP 30 Minute Shawn Murphy (Box 17, Video 297)
        - Pittsburgh Basketball vs Villanova, January 19, 1999; Betacam SP 90 Minute Tape 1 of 2 (Box 17, Video 314)
        - Pittsburgh Basketball vs Villanova, January 19, 1999; Betacam SP 90 Minute Tape 2 of 2 (Box 17, Video 313)
        - WTAE Sportscast "Midnight Madness", November 15, 1999; Betacam SP 20 Minute Needs Case (Box 17, Video 294)
        - Pittsburgh @ Notre Dame, January 22, 2000; Betacam SP 30 Minute Paul Karlsson (Box 17, Video 298)
        - Georgetown @ Pittsburgh, February 13, 2000; Betacam SP 30 Minute Paul Karlsson (Box 17, Video 301)
        - Pittsburgh @ Georgetown, February 20, 2000; Betacam SP 30 Minute Paul Karlsson (Box 17, Video 295)
        - Rutgers @ Pittsburgh, Feburary 26, 2000; Betacam SP 30 Minute Shissler (Box 17, Video 291)
        - Pittsburgh @ Boston College, February 23, 2000; Betacam SP 30 Minute Michael Molinari (Box 17, Video 303)
        - '01 Big East Tournament Pitt vs. MIA - Elvis Melt, March 7, 2001; Betacam SP 90 Minute (Box 11, Video 185)
        - 01 Big East Tournament Pittsburgh v. Miami, March 7, 2001; Betacam SP 90 Minute Tape 1 of 2 (Box 11, Video 190)
        - 01 Big East Tournment Pitt v. Miami, March 7, 2001; Betacam SP 90 Minute Tape 2 of 2 (Box 11, Video 189)
        - '01 Big East Tournament Pitt v. ND / Prov v Syr - Elvis Melt, March 8, 2001; Betacam SP 90 Minute (Box 11, Video 183)
        - '01 Big East Tournament Elvis Melt, March 9, 2001; Betacam SP 90 Minute (Box 11, Video 184)
        - '01 Big East Tournament Pitt vs. Syr, March 9, 2001; Betacam SP 90 Minute Tape 1 of 2 (Box 11, Video 187)
        - '01 Big East Tournament Pitt vs. Syr, March 9, 2001; Betacam SP 90 Minute Tape 2 of 2 (Box 11, Video 186)
        - 01 Big East Tournament Boston College v. Pittsburgh, March 10, 2001; Betacam SP 90 Minute (Box 11, Video 188)
        - 01 Big East Tournament BC vs. Pitt Post-Game and Melt, March 10, 2001; Betacam SP 90 Minute (Box 11, Video 191)
        - '01 Big East Tournament Pittsburgh v. notre Dame, March 8, 2001; Betacam SP 90 Minute Tape 2 of 2 (Box 11, Video 182)
        - Mens Basketball Senior Hilites Uconn, unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute Tape 1 of 2 Needs Case (Box 17, Video 288)
        - Mens Bball Senior Hilites Uconn, unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute Tape 2 of 2 Needs Case (Box 17, Video 290)
        - Pitt vs Oklahoma #1, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCS-20BRS 1st half Tape 1 of ? Needs Case (Box 17, Video 284)
        - Pitt vs Oklahoma #3, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCS-20BRS 1st Half and Half Time Tape 3 of ? Needs Case (Box 17, Video 285)
        - Pittsburgh Basketball: Highlight Video, unknown; VHS T-10 (Box 17, Video 282)
        - "Mann in Media" Basketball Script, June 4, 1990; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 20 (Box 17, Video 293)
        - George von Benko Basketball Play by Play, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic 20 HG (Box 17, Video 309)
        - Pittsburgh Basketball vs Connecticut, January 16, 1999; Betacam SP 90 Minute Tape 1 of 2 (Box 17, Video 312)
        - Pittsburgh Basketball vs Connecticut, January 16, 1999; Betacam SP 90 Minute Tape 2 of 2 (Box 17, Video 310)
        - Pitt Midnight Madness, unknown; Betacam SP 60 Minute (Box 17, Video 300)
        - "Pitt Basketball Preseason", unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 (Box 17, Video 304)
        - Pitt vs. Georgetown Tape 3, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCS-20BRS Tape 3 of ? (Box 19, Video 411)
        - Pitt vs. Georgetown Tape 4, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCS-20BRS Tape 4 of ? (Box 19, Video 412)
        - "Pitt vs. Georgetown" Tape 3, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCS-20BRS Tape 3 of ? (Box 19, Video 384)
        - "Pitt vs. Georgetown" Tape 4, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic KSC-20BRS Tape 4 of ? (Box 19, Video 385)
        - "Pitt vs. Georgetown", January 27, 1991; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCS-20BRS Tape 1 of ? (Box 19, Video 409)
        - Pitt vs. Georgetown Tape 1, January 27, 1991; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCS-20BRS Tape 1 of ? (Box 19, Video 383)
        - Pitt vs. Georgetown, January 27, 1991; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCS-20BRS Tape 2 of ? (Box 19, Video 385)
        - Pitt vs. Georgetown Tape 5, January 27, 1991; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCS-20BRS Tape 5 of ? (Box 19, Video 413)
        - "Pitt vs. Georgetown", January 2, 1986; 3/4 Inch U-matic BCA-60 Tape 3 of 3 (Box 19, Video 392)
        - Pitt vs. Georgetown Tape 1, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCS-20BRS Tape 1 of ? (Box 19, Video 410)
        - Pitt vs. Villanova, February 23, 1987; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCA 60 Tape 1 of ? (Box 19, Video 794)
        - Pitt vs. Villanova, February 23, 1987; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCA 10 Tape 2 of ? (Box 19, Video 354)
        - "Pitt vs. Syracuse" Tape #1, February 7, 1983; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 Tape 1 of ? (Box 19, Video 389)
        - Pitt Basketball Practice, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCS 20 (Box 19, Video 387)
        - Chanselor #2 Basketball Game, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCS 20 (Box 19, Video 415)
        - Pitt Basketball vs. Moble Oil #1, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCS 20 (Box 19, Video 414)
        - "Pitt vs Illinois" 92-93 Season (Tape #2), February 13, 1993; Betacam SP 90 Minute Tape 2 of ? (Box 21, Video 378)
        - Villanova at Pitt #2 Basketball, February 7, 1986; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 (Box 22, Video 462)
        - Darelle Porter Feature on the Big East Network (Basketball - Pre-Season Special '88), unknown; VHS T-120 (Box 24, Video 430)
        - Pitt Basketball Special, January 16, 1988; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 30 (Box 24, Video 432)
        - Pitt Basketball Selects, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-Matic KSP-S20 Needs Case (Box 24, Video 435)
        - Pitt vs. Boston College, January 30, 1988; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 Tape 2 of 2 (Box 24, Video 469)
        - Pitt vs. Arizona #1, September 24, 1979; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 Tape 1 of ? (Box 24, Video 472)
        - Portee[sic](Porter) For Pitt, unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic KSP-S20 (Box 25, Video 516)
        - "Pitt vs St. Francis, Marshall, Georgetown, Cornell, Robert Morris, UCLA, Providence & Miami" (Tape #1), unknown; Betacam SP 60 Minute Tape 1 of ? Needs Case (Box 25, Video 475)
        - "Pitt vs. Syracuse, Villanova, St John's, Seton Hall, Illinois, Boston College, Uconn, Providence, Georgetown, Villanova, etc., (Tape #3), unknown; Betacam SP 90 Minute Tape 3 of ? (Box 25, Video 492)
        - Basketball Highlights 1993-1994 Tape 3, April 3, 1994; Betacam SP 30 Minute Tape 3 of ? (Box 25, Video 480)
        - Bill 4 Knight DUB - From OCDL Film(?), unknown; 3/4 Inch U-matic MBR 5s (Box 25, Video 494)
        - 1994 Pitt Basketball Players - Eric Mobley & Jason Maile, unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute (Box 25, Video 497)
        - Pitt-PC B-Ball, unknown; VHS T-120 (Box 26, Video 500)
        - "Pitt Basketball Highlights" / "Big East / Highlight Package", unknown; VHS (Box 26, Video 504)
        - Pitt Basketball Preseason Special - '89-'90, November 17, 1989; VHS T-120 (Box 26, Video 505)
        - Basketball - Pitt vs. Connecticut (L 79-61), January 6, 1990; VHS T-120 (Box 26, Video 506)
        - Basketball Highlights, unknown; VHS T-120 (Box 26, Video 507)
        - Pitt / Villanova #3, February 7, 1986; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 30 (Box 27, Video 521)
        - Basketball - Pitt vs. Miami (L 83-71) / Pitt at Penn State (W 67-65), March 12, 1992 AND March 18, 1992; VHS T-120 (Box 26, Video 508)
        - "Pitt Hoop Scenes", August 30, 2004; Betacam SP 60 Minute (Box 26, Video 511)
        - Pitt Basketball Pre-Game, December 6, 1986; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 30 7:30-8:00 (Box 27, Video 542)
        - Pitt Basketball - End of halftime to Game Completion - Reel #2, December 14, 1985; 1 Inch Videotape Tape 2 of ? (Box 28, Video 537)
        - Mark Blount Foul Oct, unknown; Betacam SP 20 Minute (Box 29, Video 557)
        - 1996-1997 Men's Basketball Headshots, unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute (Box 29, Video 574)
        - Basketball Special Preseason, unknown; VHS T-120 (Box 29, Video 572)
        - Pitt vs Boston College, February 29, 1988; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 Tape 1 of 2 (Box 30, Video 1394)
        - Pitt vs Boston College, February 29, 1988; 3/4 Inch U-matic UCA 60 Tape 2 of 2 (Box 30, Video 1395)
        - Pitt BB, unknown; VHS T-120 (Box 30, Video 598)
        - Pitt vs. St. Francis, December 1, 1990; 3/4 Inch U-matic 35 Millimeter Tape Reel 1 (Box 32, Video 632)
        - Pitt Basketball Video, unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute (Box 32, Video 637)
        - Pitt Basketball Highlights 1994-95, unknown; Betacam SP 30 Minute (Box 32, Video 639)
        - UCONN vs. Pitt - Big East Tournament, February 5, 1996; Betacam SP 20 Minute (Box 32, Video 646)
        - NCAA Hoops - Georgetown / Pittsburgh, January 2, 1986; 3/4 Inch U-matic KCA-60K 35 Millimeter Tape Tape 1 of 3 (Box 32, Video 652)